ticketbooth.com.au 2019-03-04

# Privacy Policy - Ticketbooth Support

**Effective: 25 May 2018**

#### Key Changes

  * Complete transparency with language that is easy to understand – we use clear, plain language to illustrate our activities and the ways in which we collect, use and store information about you
  * More control over your information – we make it easy for you to control the information you provide to us. Our policy explains how you can make choices about your information, and the measures we’ve put in place to keep your information secure.
  * In line with Europe’s new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

#### Ticketbooth Respects Your Privacy

Ticketbooth’s primary role is to provide event publishing, registration, ticketing and related software and services to Australian, New Zealand and other International users of Ticketbooth and the Ticketbooth platform.

Your privacy and the security of information that we collect is of utmost importance to us. This policy is intended to help you understand:

  * What information we collect about you
  * When we collect information about you
  * How we use the information we collect about you
  * How we share information that we collect
  * How we store and secure the information we collect
  * How to access and control your information
  * Other important privacy information

This Privacy Policy cover the personal information we collect about you when you use our products or services, whether that be on-site at an event, or on one of our websites, which we refer to as “Services” in this policy. “Ticketbooth”, “We” and “Us” refers to Ticketbooth Pty Ltd and Ticketbooth Limited, and any of our corporate affiliates. The term “Event Organiser” in means the venue operators and/or promotor(s) of a particular event. The term “personal information” in this Privacy Policy means any information from which your identity is apparent or can be reasonably ascertained.

This policy also explains your choices about how we use personal information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you. By accessing any of our Services, you provide consent to the collection and use of the information about you. **If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our Services or interact with any other aspect of our business.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or how we manage your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer.

We may update or revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. You can find the most current version on our websites (ticketbooth.com.au, ticketbooth.co.nz and ticketbooth.eu) or by asking our Privacy Officer for a copy.

#### What kinds of personal information does Ticketbooth collect and hold?

We collect information about you when you provide it to us, when you use our Services, and when other sources provide it to us, as further described below.

##### **Information you provide to us**

We collect information about you when you input it into the Services or otherwise provide it directly to us.

_**Account and Profile Information:**_ We collect information about you when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, set preferences, sign-up for or make purchases through the Services. For example, you provide your contact information, and in most cases, billing information, when you make a ticket purchase through the website. We keep track of your preferences when you select settings within the Services.

_**Content you provide through our websites:** _The Services also include our websites owned or operated by us. We collect other content that you submit to these websites, which include social media or social networking websites operated by us. For example, you provide content to us when you provide feedback or when you participate in any interactive features, surveys, contests, promotions, sweepstakes, activities or events.

_**Information you provide through our support channels:** _The Services also include our customer support, where you may choose to submit information regarding a problem you are experiencing with a Service. Whether you designate yourself as a technical contact, open a support ticket, speak to one of our representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support team, you will be asked to provide contact information, a summary of the problem you are experiencing, and any other documentation, screenshots or information that would be helpful in resolving the issue.

_**Payment Information:** _We collect certain payment and billing information when you use certain sections of the Services. For example, when you purchase a ticket via one of our websites, you provide payment information, such as payment card details, which we collect via secure payment processing services.

##### **Information we collect automatically when you use the Services**

We collect information about you when you use our Services, including browsing our websites and taking certain actions within the Services.

_**Your use of the Services:** _We keep track of certain information about you when you visit and interact with any of our Services. This information includes the features you use; the links you click on; the type, and how you interact with others on the Services.

_**Device and Connection Information:** _We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This device information includes your connection type and settings when you access, update, or use our Services. We also collect information through your device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device identifiers, and crash data. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better Service experience. How much of this information we collect depends on the type and settings of the device you use to access the Services.

_**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:**_ Ticketbooth and our third-party partners, such as our advertising and analytics partners, use cookies and other tracking technologies (e.g. pixels) to provide functionality and to recognise you across different Services and devices. For more information, please see our Cookies and Tracking Notice, which includes information on how to control or opt out of these cookies and tracking technologies.

##### **Information we receive from other sources**

We receive information about you from other Service users, from third-party services, from our related companies, and from our business and channel partners.

_**Other services you link to your account:** _We receive information about you when you integrate or link a third-party service with our Services. For example, if you choose to complete your ticket purchase using your Facebook credentials, we receive your name and email address as permitted by your Facebook profile settings in order to authenticate you. The information we receive when you link or integrate our Services with a third-party service depends on the settings, permissions and privacy policy controlled by that third-party service. You should always check the privacy settings and notices in these third-party services to understand what data may be disclosed to us or shared with our Services.

_**Ticketbooth and Related Companies:** _We receive information about you from companies that are owned or operated by Ticketbooth, in accordance with their terms and policies.

_**Ticketbooth Partners:** _We receive information about you and your activities on and off the Services from third-party partners, such as advertising and market research partners who provide us with information about your interest in and engagement with, our Services and online advertisements.

#### How does Ticketbooth collect information about you?

Generally, we collect personal information when you use one of our Services, such as one of the examples below:

  * make a purchase through our network which includes our website, call centre, or box offices;
  * register for a Ticketbooth account via our website;
  * participate in a Ticketbooth survey, competition, promotion or other marketing campaign;
  * indicate that you wish to receive news, offers or other marketing material from Ticketbooth;
  * sign up to a waitlist or an event;
  * make an inquiry or a complaint;
  * have other dealings with us, for example, via social media or in person, over the phone or when you write to us.

In certain circumstances, we may also collect personal information about you in the course of combining and analysing different data sets which, in and of themselves, may not contain personal information.

**Sometimes we collect personal information about you from other sources, for example:**

  * our related companies which include Audiencetools Pty Ltd and Token Systems Pty Ltd;
  * people making a purchase on your behalf;
  * our business clients such as venues, promoters and sporting clubs; or
  * third party suppliers and contractors who assist us to operate our business, such as: 
    * information technology suppliers
    * marketing and digital services suppliers
    * research and development organisations
    * data partners
    * analytics consultants; and
    * publicly available sources of information

Also, from time to time Ticketbooth collects personal information about individuals who are not customers. This is usually where we collect the name and business contact details of a person who is the contact in a government agency or company with whom we deal. Ticketbooth’s policy is to only use personal information collected from non-customers for the main business purpose for which it was collected.

#### How does Ticketbooth use the information that we collect about you?

Generally, Ticketbooth only uses personal information for the primary purpose for which we have collected it, or for another closely related secondary purpose. How we use the information we collect depends in part on which Services you use, how you use them, and any preferences you have communicated to us. Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you.

_**To provide the Services:**_ We use information about you to provide the Services to you, such as online ticket sales for an event, and to monitor the use of such Services.

_**For research and development:**_ We are always looking for ways to make our Services smarter, faster, secure, integrated, and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people use our Services and feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for integration and improvement of the Services. In some cases, we apply these learnings across our Services to improve and develop similar features or to better integrate the services you use.

_**To communicate with you about the Services:** _We use your contact information to send transactional communications via email and within the Services. We also provide tailored communications based on your activity and interactions with us. For example, reminder emails that contain your tickets for events your have purchased for, or to contact you if there is an event cancellation or change in event details. These communications are part of the Services and in most cases you cannot opt out of them. If an opt out is available, you will find that option within the communication itself or in your account settings.

_**To market, promote and drive engagement with the Services:** _We use your contact information and information about how you use the Services to send promotional communications that may be of specific interest to you, including by email and by displaying Ticketbooth ads on other companies’ websites and applications, as well as on platforms like Facebook and Google. These communications are aimed at driving engagement and maximising what you get out of the Services, including information about new features, newsletters, and events we think may be of interest to you. We also communicate with you about offers, promotions and contests.

_**Customer support:** _We use your information to resolve technical issues you may encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, to analyse crash information, and to repair and improve the Services. For example if you are having difficulty completing your purchase, or request that we re-send your tickets to you.

_**For safety and security:** _We use information about you and your Service use to verify accounts and activity, to monitor suspicious or fraudulent activity and to identify violations of Service policies. For example, we use personal information collected to detect and prevent ticket scalping and unauthorised ticket on-selling.

_**To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights:** _Where required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we use information about you in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, and audit functions, and disclosures in connection with the acquisition, merger or sale of a business.

_**With your consent:** _We use information about you where you have given us consent to do so for a specific purpose not listed above. For example, we may publish testimonials or featured customer stories to promote the Services, with your permission.

_**Legal bases for processing (for EEA users):**_ If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal bases depend on the Services you use and how you use them. This means we collect and use your information only where:

  * We need it to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalised features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Services and to protect our legal rights and interests;
  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place. Where we are using your information because we or a third party have a legitimate interest to do so, you have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Services.

As noted later in this policy this information will be shared and may be used by parent companies, subsidiaries and/or affiliates for purposes consistent with this policy.

From time to time, there may be other purposes for which we collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information. We will tell you about these at the point of collection.

#### How does Ticketbooth share the information that we collect?

We share information we collect about you in the ways discussed below, including in connection with possible business transfers, but we are not in the business of selling information about you to advertisers or other third parties.

##### **Sharing with other Service users**

When you use the Services, we share certain information about you with other Service users.

_**Managed accounts and administrators:**_ If you register or access the Services using an email address with a domain that is owned by your employer or organisation, and such organisation wishes to establish an account, certain information about you including your name, contact info, content and past use of your account may become accessible to that organisation’s administrator and other Service users sharing the same domain. If you are an administrator for a particular site or group of users within the Services, we may share your contact information with current or past Service users, for the purpose of facilitating Service-related requests.

_**Community Forums:** _Our websites offer publicly accessible blogs, such as the Ticketbooth Blog. You should be aware that any information you provide on these websites – including profile information associated with the account you use to post the information – may be read, collected, and used by any member of the public who accesses these websites. Your posts and certain profile information may remain even after you terminate your account. We urge you to consider the sensitivity of any information you input into these Services. To request removal of your information from publicly accessible websites operated by us, please contact us as provided below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to and why.

##### **Sharing with third parties**

We share information with third parties that help us operate, provide, improve, integrate, customise, support and market our Services.

_**Service Providers:** _We work with third-party service providers to provide website and application development, hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, virtual infrastructure, payment processing, analysis and other services for us, which may require them to access or use information about you. If a service provider needs to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under close instruction from us, including policies and procedures designed to protect your information.

_**Ticketbooth Partners:** _We work with third parties who provide consulting, sales, and technical services to deliver and implement customer solutions around the Services. We may share your information with these third parties in connection with their services, such as to assist with payments, to provide localised support, and to provide customisations. We may also share information with these third parties where you have agreed to that sharing.

_**Promoters, venue operators and sponsors:**_ We may disclose your personal information to any promoters, venue operators and sponsors of events for which you use the Services for operational purposes. If you consent, these organisations may use this information to provide you with promotional and marketing material about their events. You may update your preference to receive any promotional or marketing material at any time directly with the organisations which have obtained your information. If you do not have have their details, you can contact us directly. This privacy policy does not cover how these organisations use your information.

_**Third Party Apps:** _Through your use of the Services, you may be explicitly asked to allow third-party apps to access your information. Doing so may give third-party apps access to your account and information about you like your name and email address, and any content you choose to use in connection with those apps. Third-party app policies and procedures are not controlled by us, and this privacy policy does not cover how third-party apps use your information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of third parties before connecting to or using their applications or services to learn more about their privacy and information handling practices. If you object to information about you being shared with these third parties, you should decline when this is explicitly asked, however this may result in an inability to use the Services.

_**Social Media Widgets:** _The Services may include links that direct you to other websites or services whose privacy practices may differ from ours. Your use of and any information you submit to any of those third-party sites is governed by their privacy policies, not this one.

_**Third-Party Widgets:** _Some of our Services contain widgets and social media features, such as the Facebook ‘Share’ button. These widgets and features collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on the Services, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Widgets and social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

_**With your consent:** _We share information about you with third parties when you give us consent to do so.

_**Compliance with Enforcement Requests and Applicable Laws; Enforcement of Our Rights**_ : In exceptional circumstances, we may share information about you with a third party if we believe that sharing is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, including to meet national security requirements, (b) enforce our agreements, policies and terms of service, (c) protect the security or integrity of our products and services, (d) protect Ticketbooth, our customers or the public from harm or illegal activities, or (e) respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith requires us to disclose information to assist in preventing the death or serious bodily injury of any person.

##### **Sharing with affiliated companies**

We share information we collect with affiliated companies and, in some cases, with prospective affiliates. Affiliated companies are companies owned or operated by us. The protections of this privacy policy apply to the information we share in these circumstances.

_**Ticketbooth and Related Companies:** _We share information we have about you with other Ticketbooth corporate affiliates in order to operate and improve products and services and to offer other Ticketbooth affiliated services to you. This includes companies that own or operate the services listed here.

_**Business Transfers:** _We may share or transfer information we collect under this privacy policy in connection with any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on the Services if a transaction takes place, as well as any choices you may have regarding your information.

#### How does Ticketbooth store and secure the personal information it collects?

Ticketbooth may hold your personal information in electronic or hard copy format or a combination of both. This personal information may be combined or linked with other information held about, or which we attribute to you.

We have taken a number of physical, electronic and procedural steps to protect your personal information from misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

##### **Information storage and security**

Your personal information, even if collected within your home country, may be transferred to and stored in a country that is not the same as where it was collected on a temporary or permanent basis.

We protect the personal information we collect in a secure database stored by our third party data storage provider. Data collected online is stored in a two-step authenticated, encrypted private access only bucket. Ticketbooth also employs firewalls, intrusion detection systems and virus scanning tools to protect against unauthorised persons and viruses from entering our systems.

Ticketbooth employees are required, as a condition of their employment, to treat personal information held by Ticketbooth as confidential, and to maintain the confidentiality of that personal information. They are also required to sign in and use a password when accessing Ticketbooth systems, and are only granted access to parts of the system, or subsects of personal information, as required.

While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others.

##### **How long we keep information**

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information provided. After such time, we will either delete or anonymise your information or, if this is not possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible.

However, we may retain Personal Data for an additional period as is permitted or required under applicable laws. Even if we delete your Personal Data it may persist on backup or archival media for an additional period of time for legal, tax or regulatory reasons or for legitimate and lawful business purposes.

_**Account information:**_ We retain your account information for as long as your account is active and a reasonable period thereafter in case you decide to re-activate the Services. We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations, and to continue to develop and improve our Services. Where we retain information for Service improvement and development, we take steps to eliminate information that directly identifies you, and we only use the information to uncover collective insights about the use of our Services, not to specifically analyse personal characteristics about you.

_**Information you share on the Services:**_ If your account is deactivated or disabled, some of your information and the content you have provided will remain in order to allow your team members or other users to make full use of the Services. For example, if you are a user who originally set up the Organisation, we may retain your data as the original owner of that Organisation.

_**Marketing information:** _If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest in our Services. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created.

##### **Privacy Shield Notice**

Ticketbooth and its subsidiaries act in accordance with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks and the Privacy Shield Principles regarding the collection, use, and retention of information about you that is transferred from the European Union or Switzerland to the U.S.

We ensure that the Privacy Shield Principles apply to all information about you that is subject to this privacy policy and is received from the European Union, the European Economic Area, and Switzerland.

To learn more about the Privacy Shield Program please see here [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/).

#### How to access and control the information that Ticketbooth collects about you?

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your information in a structured, electronic format.

If you would like to access, correct or delete information we hold about you, or opt-out of communication, please contact our Privacy Officer.

Your request and choices may be limited in certain cases: for example, if fulfilling your request would reveal information about another person, or if you ask to delete information which we or your administrator are permitted by law or have compelling legitimate interests to keep. Where you have asked us to share data with third parties, for example, by installing third-party apps, you will need to contact those third-party service providers directly to have your information deleted or otherwise restricted.

#### Other important privacy information

##### **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on the Services homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Services and deactivate your account(s), as outlined above.

##### **How to contact our Privacy Officer**

Our Privacy Officer can be contacted by:

  * email at [privacy@ticketbooth.com.au](mailto:privacy@ticketbooth.com.au)
  * mail at Ticketbooth Pty Ltd, PO Box 388, Strawberry Hills, NSW 2012 Australia
